cyclingtimetrials.org.uk 2018-12-22

# Cycling Time Trials: Data Privacy Notice

### **Scope**

This document provides you with information about how we are handling, or are intending to handle, your personal information:

If you are aged 16 or under, please get your parent/guardian’s permission before you provide any personal information to us.

### **About us**

Cycling Time Trials (“CTT”) is committed to protecting and respecting your privacy and complying with the principles of applicable data protection laws.  This notice sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us.  Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it.  The data controller of the personal data referred to in this policy is Cycling Time Trials Limited whose registered office is at c/o DJH Accountants, Porthill Lodge, High Street, Wolstanton, Newcastle under Lyme, Staffordshire, ST5 0EZ.

### **Collection of personal data**

CTT may collect and/or create or otherwise obtain and process the following data about you:

  * Information about you that you provide by filling in forms (whether paper forms or online via the CTT website) while entering events held under the jurisdiction of CTT or when you register for activities promoted by CTT.
  * Information that you provide on your CTT profile page on the CTT website.
  * Information about you (primarily contact details) that you provide to CTT in your capacity as a CTT Board member, CTT District official or as an organiser of an event promoted under CTT’s rules and regulations.
  * Information contained in an accident report form should you be involved in an accident in a CTT event or be associated with or a witness to such an accident.

This includes information provided at the time of registering to use the online entry system via the CTT website, subscribing to our communications, posting material, entering, attending and volunteering at events, joining clubs or requesting further services.

  * Information from your social media accounts but only where you have given us permission to use it. For example, posts, pictures and video footage you share on sites such as Facebook and Twitter.
  * We may also ask you for information when you report a problem or make a complaint and, if you contact us, we may keep a record of that correspondence.
  * We may also ask you to complete optional surveys that we use for research purposes and to provide you with a more relevant customer experience.
  * Details of when you digitally interact with CTT via our websites and other digital channels and the resources that you access which may include the use of cookies (subject to our Cookie policy).
  * Information about emails and other communications we have sent to you and your interaction with them.
  * Information from third parties where you consent to those other organisations sharing information they hold on you with us, and where those other organisations lawfully share your information with us.
  * We may use a photograph of you taken at a CTT event whether competing or at the prize presentation which may be used for promotional purposes (e.g. in the CTT handbook, on the CTT website, in the CTT newsletter or in the CTT annual report.

### **Uses made of your information and the basis of processing**

CTT will use your personal information to:

  * Ensure that content from our websites is presented in the most effective manner;
  * Authenticate you when you register;
  * Carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and CTT;
  * Provide you with information, products or services that you request from CTT or which we feel may interest you, where we are legally entitled to do so;
  * Notify you about changes to our service;
  * To gather statistics about the number of participants in CTT events and the number of people registered with CTT; or
  * Publish and maintain a comprehensive set of results and rankings for the sport of time trialling.

If you are a CTT District official, your contact details (name, postal address, telephone number and email address), will be published in the annual CTT handbook and on the CTT website.  Such details may also be published on your CTT District website or in your CTT District handbook.

If you are the organiser of an event to be promoted under CTT’s rules and regulations, your contact details (name, postal address, telephone number and email address), will be published in the annual CTT handbook and on the CTT website.  Such details may also be published on the relevant CTT District website or in the relevant CTT District handbook.

If you enter an event promoted under CTT’s rules and regulations, the information provided by you on your entry form (whether you use the CTT online entry system or the standard CTT paper entry form) will be used for the purposes of the promotion of such event.  Certain information provided by you may be published on the start sheet and result sheet for the event (both of which will be made public and may be published on the CTT website or shared on social media) although will be limited to your name, gender, age or age category and the affiliated club or team of which you are a member.  In some cases, your personal best time or distance or your best performance in the last three years may also be published on the start sheet.  In the case of the result sheet, your recorded time or distance in the event will also be published.  Such details may also be used for the purpose of a ranking system or points competition compiled by CTT, a CTT District, Veterans Time Trial Association or a regional time trial association.

If you are named as the “contact” for a club or organisation affiliated to CTT, the contact details you provide will be shown on the CTT website.  Such contact details will be used by CTT (and by CTT District officials) for the purpose of contacting you as the representative of such club or organisation.

CTT will not use any of the personal information we collect from you to make automated business decisions.

CTT websites:

  * cyclingtimetrials.org.uk
  * theraceoftruth.org.uk
  * sandbox.cyclingtimetrials.org.uk
  * organisers.cyclingtimetrials.org.uk

CTT District websites:

  * East – www.eastdistrictca.org.uk
  * Lincolnshire – http://community.lincolnshire.gov.uk/cttlincs/
  * London East – www.cttlondoneast.org.uk
  * London North – www.lndc.org.uk
  * London South – www.londonsouthdc.org.uk
  * London West – www.londonwestdc.co.uk
  * Manchester – www.manchesterctt.org.uk
  * North Midlands – cttnorthmidlands.org
  * South – www.southdc.org.uk
  * South-East – www.cttsoutheastdistrict.org.uk
  * South Wales – southwalesdc.co.uk
  * South West – www.southwesttimetrials.org
  * West – www.westdc.co.uk

If your CTT District does not currently have a website, it may do so in the future.

The legal basis on which we collect and process the personal data described above depends on the personal information concerned and the specific context in which we collect it.  However, we will only use your personal information where we:

  * Have your consent to do so;
  * Need the personal data to perform a contract with you;
  * Need to process your personal information (primarily contact details) in your capacity as a CTT District official or CTT event organiser;
  * Need to process your personal information so as to facilitate you competing in an event you have entered which is to be held under CTT’s rules and regulations;
  * Need to process your personal information for our legitimate interests and only where our legitimate interests are not overridden by your data protection interests or fundamental rights and freedoms;
  * Have a legal obligation to collect personal information from you; or
  * Need the personal information to protect your vital interests or those of another person.

If we ask you to provide personal information to comply with a legal requirement or to perform a contract with you, we will make this clear at the relevant time, and advise you whether the provision of your personal information is mandatory or not (as well as the possible consequences if you do not provide your personal information).

### **Information security**

CTT will take all steps reasonably necessary including policies, procedures and security features to ensure that your data is treated securely and protected from unauthorised and unlawful access and/or use, and in accordance with this notice.  Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure and, although we will do our best to protect your personal data transmitted to us via the internet, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our website from your device.  Any transmission is at your own risk. 

Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of the website, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential.  We ask you not to share such a password with anyone.

Where any payments are being collected on our behalf, we require our payment providers to be compliant with the Payment Card Industry’s Data Security standards (PCI-DSS).

### **Recipients of personal data**

We will share information about you with some of our suppliers who process data on our behalf to help us to provide services to you.  We undertake this data sharing on the basis of our legitimate interests.

Categories of organisation and purpose

  * **Marketing agencies** \- to provide relevant digital content to our customers
  * **Website hosting companies** \- to host CTT digital platforms (e.g. CTT website) and associated customer databases to enable customers to log in and interact with the website
  * **Email broadcasting companies** \- to send emails to our customers
  * **SMS broadcasting companies** \- to send SMS and text messages to our customers
  * **Mailing houses** \- to send products and benefits to our customers that are not directly produced by CTT (e.g. publications)
  * **Governing bodies of cycling** \- to assist in event management and disciplinary issues
  * **UK Anti** **-Doping** – to enable CTT to conduct effective anti-doping measures
  * **CTT’s insurance brokers and insurance policy underwriters -** in the event of a claim made by a third party against a competitor whilst competing in an event held under CTT’s rules and regulations or against the event organiser or a volunteer (or volunteers) appointed by the event organiser to assist with the promotion of such event
  * **CTT event organisers and CTT officials**  \- to enable event organisers and officials to manage CTT events and activities and communicate with participants
  * **CTT affiliated cycling club officials** \- to enable clubs to communicate with and administer activities for those belonging to their club or group
  * **CTT District officials** \- to manage cycling events, clubs, groups and volunteers
  * **Sports results agencies** \- to collate results and reports for the CTT website on behalf of CTT and for the national press

### **International transfer of personal data**

The information we collect may be transferred to organisations who may store and use such data at premises in other countries.  Where we allow an organisation to process your personal information outside of the European Economic Area, we will ensure that we create and maintain appropriate safeguards with those organisations so that your personal information is subject to the same standards and protections as when we are processing your personal information inside the European Economic Area.

### **Data retention period**

We will hold information about you in our data systems only for as long as we need it for the purpose for which we collected it, which is as follows:

  * As long as you continue to log into our website or use our services (including engaging with emails, entering cycling events or downloading content) we will retain and process information about you.   In such cases, you will be considered to be an ‘active’ customer.  If you have not been ‘active’ as a customer for a period of three years, CTT will deactivate your customer account and subject to the data retention periods referred to below anonymise any personal data relating to you.

  * Any data relating to the obligations of CTT to maintain a comprehensive, published index of results as a National Governing Body for time trialling will be retained.  This would not include more than name, age or age category, gender, and name of the club affiliated to CTT of which the individual is a member; alongside details of the event in which an individual took part.

  * Personal data linked to the processing of insurance claims, subject access requests, disputes, safeguarding investigations, anti-doping, disciplinary or police matters will only be kept for as long as it necessary for those purposes, as each is applicable.
  * Personal data provided by you when entering a time trial held under the rules and regulations of CTT normally will be retained for a period of four years following the date of the event and in the event of an accident in an event involving a competitor who is aged under 18 years for the period of four years from and including that competitor’s 18th birthday.  This is needed should there be a claim made against a competitor or other person associated with such event.

### **IP addresses and cookies**

We may collect information about your computer, including where available your IP address, operating system and browser type, for system administration and to report aggregate information to our advertisers.  This is statistical data about our users' browsing actions and patterns and does not identify any individual.

For the same reason, we may obtain information about your general internet usage by using a cookie file which is stored on the hard drive of your computer.  Cookies contain information that is transferred to your computer's hard drive.

You may refuse to accept cookies by activating the setting on your browser which allows you to refuse the setting of cookies.  However, if you select this setting you may be unable to access certain parts of the CTT website.  Unless you have adjusted your browser setting so that it will refuse cookies, our system will issue cookies when you log on to the CTT website.  

In addition to cookies, CTT records the activity of users signed in to our websites in order to help us improve your customer experience and provide you with support.

The cookies used on the CTT websites are listed below.

_ga

Issued by cyclingtimetrials.org.uk

Expires: 2 years

Use: Google analytics to distinguish users

| 

_gat

Issued by cyclingtimetrials.org.uk

Expires: 10 minutes

Use: Rate limiting for Google analytics  
  
---|---  
  
CAKEPHP

Issued by cyclingtimetrials.org.uk

Expires: end of session

Use: User session information

| 

_gid

Issued by cyclingtimetrials.org.uk

Expires: 24 hours

Use: Google analytics to distinguish users  
  
### **The data subject’s rights**

Data protection laws grant you, as a Data Subject, certain ‘information rights’, which are summarised below:

  * **Right of access** \- You have the right to obtain a copy of information we hold about you
  * **Right of rectification or erasure** \- If you feel that any data that we hold about you is inaccurate, you have the right to ask us to correct or rectify it.  You also have a right to ask us to erase information about you where you can demonstrate that the data we hold is no longer needed by us, or if you withdraw the consent upon which our processing is based, or if you feel that we are unlawfully processing your data.  Please note that we may be entitled to retain your personal data despite your request, for example if we are under a separate legal obligation to retain it.  Your right of rectification and erasure extends to anyone we have disclosed your personal information to and we will take all reasonable steps to inform those with whom we have shared their data about your request for erasure.
  * **Right to restriction of processing** \- You have a right to request that we refrain from processing your data where you contest its accuracy, or the processing is unlawful and you have opposed its erasure, or where we do not need to hold your data any longer but you need us to in order to establish, exercise or defend any legal claims, or we are in dispute about the legality of our processing your personal data.
  * **Right to Portability** \- You have a right to receive any personal data that you have provided to us in order to transfer it onto another data controller where the processing is based on consent and is carried out by automated means.  This is called a data portability request.
  * **Right to Object** \- You have a right to object to our processing your personal data where the basis of the processing is our legitimate interests including but not limited to direct marketing and profiling.
  * **Right to Withdraw Consent** \- You have the right to withdraw your consent for the processing of your personal data where the processing is based on consent.
  * **Right of Complaint** \- You also have the right to lodge a complaint about any aspect of how we are handling your data with the _UK Information Commissioner’s Office,_ which can be contacted at www.ico.org.uk.
  * **Right to Opt-out of Marketing Communications** \- You have the right to opt-out of marketing communications we send to you at any time.  You can exercise this right by clicking on the “unsubscribe” or “opt-out” link in the marketing emails we send you.  To opt out of other forms of marketing (such as postal marketing or telemarketing), then please contact us using the contact details provided below.

### **Changes to this notice**

We may update this privacy notice from time to time.  When we change this notice in a material way, we will update the version date at the bottom of this page.  For significant changes to this notice we will try to give you reasonable notice unless we are prevented from doing so.  Where required by law we will seek your consent to changes in the way we use your personal information.

### **How to contact us**

If you wish to contact us about your personal data or exercise any of the rights described above please email  compliance@cyclingtimetrials.org.uk  or write to us at National Secretary (Legal & Corporate), Cycling Time Trials, c/o Nick Sharpe, Wash Farm, Wash, Chapel-en-le-Frith, High Peak, SK23 0QW

April 2018
